southbankcentre.co.uk 2017-08-29

# Privacy policy | Southbank Centre

## The personal data we collect and process

### When you use the Southbank Centre website

We receive and store certain details whenever you use the Southbank Centre website. We log your computer’s IP address and the requests it makes to our servers. Our website uses cookies to enable online transactions, to understand how people use our website and to inform our digital advertising.

If you have registered for a user account on our website then we may be able to identify you personally using a cookie set on your computer. We may track your use of the website and record this information in your user account.

### When you buy something from Southbank Centre

We collect your name and contact details when you buy tickets or other products on our website or over the phone. We maintain a record of your transaction history, but we never store your card number (although we may keep a note of the last four digits to help us identify transactions).

### When you give us information

We keep your details when you sign up to receive email from us. If you have signed up to our Access Scheme we will note this in your customer record.

### When we send you email

We keep a record of the emails we send you, and we may track whether you receive or open them (if your email software provides this information). If you click on a link in an email, we will log this. We may then track any subsequent actions online, such as buying a ticket.

## How we hold your personal information

Your personal data may be held and processed on Southbank Centre systems or systems managed by suppliers on behalf of Southbank Centre. We maintain a customer relationship management (CRM) system to hold contact details and a record of your interactions with Southbank Centre such as ticket purchases, donations, memberships, queries, complaints and attendance at special events. Where possible we aim to keep a single record for each customer.

Your data is always held securely. Access to customer information is strictly controlled. The CRM system can only be accessed by people who need it to do their job. Certain data, for example some sensitive information, is additionally controlled and is only made visible to members of staff who have a reason to work with it.

## What we use your personal information for

We use your personal information (including your name, contact details and transaction history) to fulfil your orders, provide customer service and for analysis. We may share your personal information with other organisations for these purposes. We require that such organisations meet our standards for handling data, and that it is only used for the agreed purpose. We will not otherwise share your personal information with third party organisations, except as described below.

We use some of the information we collect about you, such as the record of the events you have attended, what you’ve told us you’re interested in, to tailor the marketing and fundraising communications we send to you (if you have opted in).

## Opting into and out of marketing and fundraising communications

When you register for a user account on our website you can choose whether you would like to receive marketing and fundraising communications from Southbank Centre by email or post. Once you have a user account, you can manage your preferences at any time in the ‘My Account’ section of the website. We will not contact you for marketing and fundraising purposes unless one of these boxes is ticked. We will include opt-out instructions in any marketing or fundraising communications you receive from us.

Many of the events at Southbank Centre are presented in partnership with other companies such as with our Resident Orchestras and other artistic organisations and promoters. If you select either the Email or Post option under ‘I would like to hear about events, news and offers from the artists or companies presenting the events I’ve booked’, we will tell the relevant companies that you would like to hear from them, and we will let them know about your booking. This means that we will give them your name and contact details. We will not share sensitive information or your payment details.

We sell tickets on behalf of our Resident Orchestras, and we share our customer relationship database with them. If you buy a ticket from southbankcentre.co.uk for a Resident Orchestra’s perfomance, your name, contact details and records of the tickets you have bought will be visible to that orchestra. The orchestra will use your data for for customer service and analysis. If you select either the Email or Post option under ‘I would like to hear about events, news and offers from the artists or companies presenting the events I’ve booked’, the Resident Orchestra may additionally contact you for marketing purposes.

If you would like us to stop sending your data to our partners, you can change your preferences in the My Account section of our website. If we have already given your data to another company, we can’t remove you from their mailing list. To opt in or out of marketing or other communications from another company, please get in touch with them directly. They should always provide instructions for opting out in any marketing or other communications you receive. If you need help, please contact us.

## Other communications

If you have opted out of marketing communications, we may still get in touch with you. For example we may email you to give you important information about the events you’ve booked or to tell you about any changes.

You may be included in our market research even if you have opted out of marketing communications. You will be given the opportunity to opt out in any message you receive from us.

Southbank Centre is a charity, and we actively raise money towards a broad range of projects and ongoing work. We keep a record in our database of your donations to Southbank Centre, including memberships.

From time to time we may analyse our database to find people who we think might be able to support us based on factors such as previous contributions, transaction history and demographics. We may note other relevant information about you in our database. This could be information that you have given us yourself, information from publicly available sources, or information shared by other organisations with your consent.

To make sure that you only receive fundraising communications or invitations to support us which are relevant, we may use third parties who collate available information about you, and who undertake research to assess ability or likely interest in supporting our work.

If you have opted in to receive marketing communications by email, you may also receive fundraising messages from us. We try to make these as relevant to you as we can. You can opt out of fundraising communications at any time by replying to any message you receive from us.

## Sensitive information

Sometimes we ask you to provide sensitive information, for example when you book for certain events or participate in some activities, or when you apply for a job. As with all the personal information we hold, sensitive information is held securely and restricted to those who need to use it. We will delete sensitive information when we no longer need it.
